Amit Sharma

TECHNICAL CONTENT WRITER/EDITOR

Introduction

Go-getter technical writer and editor with 9+ yrs of exp of working with startups to world's leading companies in Healthcare, SaaS, product engineering and cloud computing. Conversant with the latest technologies and platforms like Salesforce, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Azure, IoT, DevOps and others. Proficient at developing high-quality documentation of complex software products. Proven experience in inbound marketing and email automation.

Skills

- Editing/ Proofreading
- HTML, CSS, Python, Js
- SEO
- Content Strategy
- Thorough research and analysis
- · Inbound Marketing
- SEO optimization
- Social Media Campaigns
- Video Editing
- Content management systems (CMS)
- · SQL, Power BI
- · Collaboration and teamwork
- · Attention to detail







Portfolio

<u>LinkedIn</u>: @amitvsharmaa

Content Portfolio:

https://amitvsharmaa.journoportfolio.com/

Work Experience

Sr. Content Writer/Editor
Rishabh Software - Ahmedabad | Jun 2023 to Present

- Develop and execute content strategies that align with the company's expertise in Azure, AWS, and Microsoft Power Platform development.
- Create high-quality and SEO-optimized blog posts, whitepapers, case studies, and technical documentation to showcase the company's capabilities and thought leadership.
- Collaborate closely with subject matter experts and developers to gather technical insights and ensure accuracy in content creation.
- Oversee content distribution across various platforms, including the company website, social media channels, and industry forums.
- Analyze content performance metrics to refine strategies, improve engagement, and drive increased website traffic.

Growth Manager

Astreem - Singapore | Remote - Ahmedabad | May 2022 to April 2023

- Managed the development of brand marketing strategy that increased traffic and conversions by penetrating new franchise segments through use of strategic marketing initiatives.
- Developed and implemented comprehensive digital marketing strategies for franchise clients, resulting in a 129% increase in online brand visibility and 39% growth in customer acquisition.
- Led a cross-functional team of SEO specialists, providing guidance and support in campaign planning, execution, and optimization.
- Conducted market research and competitor analysis to identify new digital marketing opportunities and stay ahead of industry trends.
- Managed multi-channel digital campaigns, including search engine optimization (SEO), pay-per-click (PPC) advertising, email marketing, social media marketing, and content marketing.

Instructional Designer | Salesforce Global Partner

Copado - Chicago, U.S. | Remote - Ahmedabad | Oct 2021 to May 2022

- Responsible creating LMS and various community initiatives for Salesforce community program.
- Developed compelling copy, headlines, sub-headlines, subject lines, CTAs, and conduct A/B tests for all email campaigns, event promotions, event follow-ups
- Worked closely with email marketing specialists and design teams to create email templates, conduct A/B tests, and deploy email campaigns.
- Monitored and reported weekly email marketing campaign performance, preparing PowerPoint presentations.

Technical Content Writer | Salesforce Global Partner

Flosum Salesforce - California | Remote - Ahmedabad | Oct 2020 to Oct 2021

- Develop and execute content strategies that align with the company's expertise in Azure, AWS, and Microsoft Power Platform development.
- Create high-quality and SEO-optimized blog posts, whitepapers, case studies, and technical documentation to showcase the company's capabilities and thought leadership.
- Collaborate closely with subject matter experts and developers to gather technical insights and ensure accuracy in content creation.
- Oversee content distribution across various platforms, including the company website, social media channels, and industry forums.
- Analyze content performance metrics to refine strategies, improve engagement, and drive increased website traffic.

Content Marketing Manager

Analytix Solutions - Ahmedabad | May 2019 to Oct 2020

- Managed content marketing for industries such as US CPA industry, , Medical Billing industry, IT, AV, and Hospitality industry.
- Organized online webinars and industry events for the CPA industry during the pandemic.
- Worked with the BD team on lead generation activities for the Boston region.
- Created engaging thought leadership content blogs, marketing,& newsletters.
- Directed content marketing strategy including planning, executing, maintaining and evolving website copy, emails, social media campaigns, acquisition ads and sales collaterals while also being responsible for writing, editing, reviewing, proofing and publishing content.
- Responsible for monitoring, tracking and measuring content marketing for each of the different industry verticals in collaboration with the marketing director based in Boston.
- Experimented with video storytelling, script writing, and audio podcast for various international conferences, and company case studies.

Content Writer | B2B Digital Marketing Agency

Webential Agency - Ahmedabad | Dec 2017 - Apr 2019

- Developed 2500+ distinctive digital content for company website and blogs in collaboration with 5 other content writers for clients in NSW, Sydney and Melbourne across industries such as Automobiles, Caravan, Homecare, B2B ecommerce, professionals and IT.
- Increased domain authority for client's websites with unique SEO optimized from 50 to 5000 views per day, awarded the most high performing content writer
- Revamped website pages and ran email marketing campaigns for a leading Australian education consultancy. Single handedly increased customer engagement for the client by 80% and used SMM and email marketing to boost traffic and conversion in student admissions.

Technical Content Writer

Cygnet Infotech - Ahmedabad | Mar 2017 - Dec 2017

- Used digital marketing tools and strategies to drive lead generation for ISV segment in the the U.S.
- Managed to drive website CRO by 200% by using content, social media and guest posts for the global B2B managed IT services audience.
- Created engaging content for thought leadership and lead generation for B2B technology audiences.

Sr. Copywriter - B2B Digital Advertising Agency

Communication Crafts - Ahmedabad | Aug 2015 - Mar 2017

- Let content marketing strategy and content writing teams for 20+ national and international clients across SaaS, luxury automobile, real estate, Managed IT and ecommerce.
- Collaborated with Creative Director and copywriting team in creating all forms of content: ads, emails, social, web pages, direct mailers, in-app messaging, and newsletters for customers across buying stages.
- Built and executed content strategies create, manage, and measure highquality and high-performing content for B2B SaaS tech product company website pages, social media, email, and blog.
- Consistently awarded WoW Employee of the month for bringing high conversions though SEO and Goog

Technical Content Writer

Openxcell technolabs | Oct 2012 - Aug 2015

- Ran content writing and content marketing campaigns for mobile app development company to drive higher SERPS.
- -Received "Standout Employee" company award for dedication and efficiency. Contributed materially to a 25% increase in customer satisfaction.
- Established content marketing strategy that included substantive site-wide growth, writing 50+ technical articles and ASO for the mobile/ web dev company.
- Improved tech blog/ B2B SaaS product's website conversion rate, generated more leads and subscribers to the business newsletter...
- - Led SEO, and content marketing strategy for fashion ecommerce vertical, tech blog, tech forum, mobile app development vertical.

Advertising Copywriter - Ad Agency

Niu Media | July 2009 - Oct 2012

- - Specialized in both long-form SEO content (landing pages, blog posts, etc.) and short-form copywriting (social media, email marketing).
- -Created impactful targeted messaging for all advertising media types.
- Developed localized media strategies based on target audience.
- - Conceptualized email marketing campaigns, social media for clients across textile, pharma, Government and IT clients while adhering to brand identity.

Get in Touch

Phone: 9099964447

Email:

amitvijaysharma16@gmail.com **Addr:** Motera, Ahmedabad

Academic Qualifications

MBA Marketing: Welingkar Institute of Mgmt - Mumbai | 2007-09

B.Com: HLIC | Gujarat University | 2003